export const COSTINGA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The amount of expenditure incurred to acquire an item is",
A: "an asset",
B: "cost",
C: "expense",
D: "loss",
answer: "B. Cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A similarity of Cost Accounting and Financial Accounting information is that both are used for",
A: "cost ascertainment",
B: "cost control",
C: "decision making",
D: "pricing products",
answer: "C. Decision making",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. For costing information to be relevant it must be",
A: "addressed to a responsible person",
B: "delivered to shareholders",
C: "understood by bankers",
D: "useful for the intended purpose",
answer: "D. Useful for the intended purpose",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. An issue to consider before setting up a Cost Accounting system is",
A: "availability of a computer system",
B: "availability of electricity",
C: "profitability of the firm",
D: "the need for cost information",
answer: "D. The need for cost information",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The cost of creating and stimulating demand for a product is",
A: "distribution cost",
B: "functional cost",
C: "ordering cost",
D: "selling cost",
answer: "D. Selling cost",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The grouping of persons as equipment controllable by a manager is",
A: "cost centre",
B: "cost department",
C: "machine department",
D: "production centre",
answer: "A. Cost centre",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following is a direct expense in bread making?",
A: "Flour",
B: "Sugar",
C: "Wrapper",
D: "Yeast",
answer: "D. Yeast",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following is a selling cost?",
A: "Carriage on finished goods",
B: "Purchase of raw materials",
C: "wages of storekeeper",
D: "warehousing of raw materials",
answer: "A. Carriage on finished goods",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Maximum lead time is",
A: "25 weeks",
B: "10 weeks",
C: "7 weeks",
D: "4 weeks",
answer: "A. 25 weeks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Maximum stock level is",
A: "90,000 units",
B: "84,000 units",
C: "65,000 units",
D: "28,000 units",
answer: "B. 84,000 units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Minimum stock level is",
A: "28,000 units",
B: "15,500 units",
C: "12,500 units",
D: "1,000 units",
answer: "B. 15,500 units",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Shortage of stocks during production will lead to",
A: "capital locked up in stock",
B: "high storage cost",
C: "loss of customers",
D: "pilferage of stock",
answer: "C. Loss of customers",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A cost associated with keeping too much stock is loss of",
A: "customers",
B: "interest on capital invested",
C: "profit on stocks",
D: "sales of stocks",
answer: "B. Interest on capital invested",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Physical stock count may be different from book records due to",
A: "keeping too little stock",
B: "keeping too much stock",
C: "delayed stock taking",
D: "over arid under issue of stock",
answer: "D. Over and under issue of stock",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The ideal amount of inventory to purchase at a time is",
A: "buffer stock",
B: "Economic Order Quantity",
C: "maximum stock level",
D: "re-order level",
answer: "B. Economic Order Quantity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The time rate method of labour remuneration is most suitable when",
A: "a high degree of skills is required",
B: "speed of production is essential",
C: "there is need to increase production",
D: "workers morale is to be raised",
answer: "A. A high degree of skills is required",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The incentive paid to workers for completing work earlier than scheduled is",
A: "bonus",
B: "discount",
C: "overtime premium",
D: "time rate",
answer: "A. Bonus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A minimum amount paid to workers irrespective of units produced is",
A: "guarantee wage",
B: "overtime premium",
C: "premium bonus",
D: "straight piece work",
answer: "A. Guarantee wage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The wages for Kofi who produced 260 units is",
A: "GH¢1,820",
B: "GH¢1,680",
C: "GH¢1,520",
D: "GH¢260",
answer: "C. GH¢1,520",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The wages of Modou who produced 340 units is",
A: "GH¢8,840",
B: "GH¢2,720",
C: "GH¢2,120",
D: "GH¢340",
answer: "C. GH¢2,120",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Units produced by Sahr who earned GH¢980 is",
A: "196 units",
B: "180 units",
C: "163 units",
D: "140 units",
answer: "C. 163 units",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Machine depreciation is apportioned on the basis of",
A: "cost of machine",
B: "horse power",
C: "machine hours",
D: "scrap value",
answer: "C. Machine hours",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Overhead is over-absorbed when actual overhead is",
A: "equal to absorbed overhead",
B: "less than absorbed overhead",
C: "more than absorbed overhead",
D: "not determinable",
answer: "B. Less than absorbed overhead",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Predetermined overhead absorption rates are computed to",
A: "allocate overheads",
B: "complete cost sheets",
C: "complete production",
D: "absorb overheads",
answer: "D. Absorb overheads",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Depreciation of factory building is classified as",
A: "administrative overhead",
B: "distribution overhead",
C: "production overhead",
D: "selling overhead",
answer: "C. Production overhead",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Area occupied is the most suitable basis for apportioning",
A: "canteen expenses",
B: "machine depreciation",
C: "power",
D: "store rent",
answer: "D. Store rent",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Costs that cannot be allocated to any cost units are",
A: "direct costs",
B: "expenses",
C: "overheads",
D: "sunk costs",
answer: "C. Overheads",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Process costing method is adopted where",
A: "a single type of product is produced in stages",
B: "customers orders are produced in batches",
C: "goods are produced to customers specification",
D: "most of the work is done on site",
answer: "A. A single type of product is produced in stages",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The objective of job costing is to",
A: "complete the work of customers",
B: "determine the cost of work-in-progress",
C: "determine the profit or loss on each job",
D: "meet customers’ specification",
answer: "C. Determine the profit or loss on each job",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The architect’s certificate shows",
A: "cost of uncompleted work",
B: "cost of complete work",
C: "profit on uncompleted contracts",
D: "value of work completed",
answer: "D. Value of work completed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Appropriate cost unit for transport industry is cost per",
A: "kilometre",
B: "passenger per kilometre",
C: "passenger per vehicle",
D: "vehicle",
answer: "B. Passenger per kilometre",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Break-even analysis assumes that the only factor that affects cost and revenue is",
A: "contribution",
B: "technology",
C: "volume",
D: "variable cost",
answer: "C. Volume",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Technology and efficiency in break-even analysis is expected to",
A: "improve with production",
B: "improve with sales",
C: "reduce with profits",
D: "remain unchanged",
answer: "D. Remain unchanged",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Break-even points in units is",
A: "492,000",
B: "92,250",
C: "30,750",
D: "5,766",
answer: "C. 30,750",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Contribution per unit is",
A: "D19.00",
B: "D16.00",
C: "D5.33",
D: "D3.00",
answer: "C. D5.33",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Variable cost per unit is",
A: "D9.00",
B: "D16.00",
C: "D13.00",
D: "D3.00",
answer: "A. D9.00",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. A budget prepared for a department is a",
A: "fixed budget",
B: "flexible budget",
C: "functional budget",
D: "master budget",
answer: "C. Functional budget",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The involvement of employees in setting standards serves as a",
A: "communication tool",
B: "control",
C: "motivating factor",
D: "planning tool",
answer: "C. Motivating factor",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. A planned statement for allocating resources by various operational sections of an organization is a",
A: "budgeted balance sheet",
B: "budgeted Profit and Loss Account",
C: "functional budget.",
D: "master budget",
answer: "C. Functional budget",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. A sales budget is a statement of planned sales in terms of",
A: "cost and revenue",
B: "cost and value",
C: "quantity and cash",
D: "quantity and value",
answer: "D. Quantity and value",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following items is included in the cash budget?",
A: "Depreciation of assets",
B: "Discounts received",
C: "Payments to supplies",
D: "Provision for bad debts",
answer: "C. Payments to supplies",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Labour efficiency variance is caused by",
A: "paying a lower rate for labour",
B: "paying a higher rate for labour",
C: "using higher grade labour",
D: "working extra hours",
answer: "C. Using higher grade labour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Standard cost is",
A: "current cost",
B: "overhead cost",
C: "predetermined cost",
D: "sunk cost",
answer: "C. Predetermined cost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A standard which is established for use over an indefinite period is",
A: "attainable standard",
B: "basic standard",
C: "current standard",
D: "ideal standard",
answer: "B. Basic standard",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The difference between actual cost and standard cost is",
A: "loss",
B: "profit",
C: "surplus",
D: "variance",
answer: "D. Variance",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Direct material cost variance consists of",
A: "efficiency and price variances",
B: "efficiency and rate variances",
C: "usage and price variances",
D: "usage and rate variances",
answer: "C. Usage and price variances",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A system of integrated accounts",
A: "charges all cost to the Cost Ledger Control Account",
B: "includes a Cost Ledger Control Account",
C: "includes a Financial Ledger Control Account",
D: "makes no distinction between Cost and Financial Accounts",
answer: "B. Includes a Cost Ledger Control Account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following appears in cost accounts only?",
A: "Direct material cost",
B: "Dividend payment",
C: "Imputed cost",
D: "Interest received",
answer: "C. Imputed cost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The balance on Work-In-Progress Account is transferred to the",
A: "Cost of Sales Account",
B: "Costing Profit and Loss Account",
C: "Finished Goods Account",
D: "Sales Account",
answer: "B. Costing Profit and Loss Account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following accounts is on the credit side of a costing trial balance?",
A: "Finished Good Control Account",
B: "General Ledger Control Account",
C: "Stores Ledger Control Account",
D: "Work-In-Progress Account",
answer: "C. Stores Ledger Control Account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]